Okay, so let's build that bubble squirt
that I just showed you in the last
video. And while it could look really
intimidating to build, I think if we
break it down into steps, it'll be a
little less intimidating. So, one of the
steps I thought that we probably should
discuss first is how do we actually swap
things positions in an array? How do we
take this five and swap it with this
four? So if we wanted to do that, what
I'll do, what you may originally think
to do is you say, well, let's just go to
the numbers array, access the zero
position, set it equal to the numbers
array in the one position. So you're
saying, take that, set it equal to that,
and then you might think you could just
say numbers position at the one equals
number's position at the zero position.
So you say take that, set it equal to
that, take that, set it equal to that.
But I'm just going to console.log log
this so you can watch it happen in real
time. So we'll come over to our window
here and we'll reload our page and you
see it says five 56 and we have now lost
our four. There's no longer a four in
this array. So what happened? Well,
anytime you've got something confusing
like that, it's helpful to just put a
break point in. So we'll reload and
we'll look at our numbers array. Our
numbers hold 4 5 6 1 2 3. And we're
about to do this next step here. So if
we hit next and then now we've paused.
So we've run one step. Now if we look at
our numbers array, it's 5 5 6 1 2 3. And
the four is nowhere to be seen. Um which
means that when we run this numbers in
the one position is five and numbers in
the zero position is five. So now when
we set the numbers in the one position
equal the numbers in the zero position,
we're setting five equal to five, which
once we've done that, we log our numbers
array and we once again get 5 6 1 2 3.
And so that's a little problematic. So
if we want to swap something, then we'll
come back over here. We need to hold on
to the information before we make a
swap. So I'm going to create a new
variable here, and I'm going to call the
call it hold number. and I'm going to
set it equal to um the numbers array at
the zero position. So what I'm doing is
I'm saying take four out and store it in
old number. Then set zeros to five.
Set the zero position to five and then
set the one position to the number that
I held outside.
So I'm saying take four out, put it
here. Put five here and then put four
back in.
So, we'll save this. We'll reload. And
if we come to here, wait, did I save it?
Hang on. I did save it. So, we'll come
here and we'll reload. And now we get 5
4 6 1 2 3. So, we've successfully
swapped five and four places. Uh, but
just to prove it, we'll reload. We'll
pause. We're about So, if we look at our
numbers array, it is 4561 23. We hit the
next button. If we look at our hold
number, it's holding four. If we hit the
next button now, if we look at our
numbers array, it's 556123.
And now we're going to put back in our
hold number. So if we hit next and we
hover over numbers, now we see it's 5 4
6 1 2 3. So we took the number out of
the array, swapped, copied over the one
number, and then put the number back
into the array. And then everything's
nice and we haven't lost any
information. So that's how we would swap
the number. So that's I'm going to hold
on to that logic here, and I'm just
going to copy it out. I'm just going to
comment it out for